Guide to the Elmer Miller Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Elmer Miller papers
1922-1972
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
1086
1086-001
Miller, Elmer,$d1898-1978
8.8 cubic feet (23 boxes) plus 6 sound cassettes
Educator, labor organization officer
Elmer Miller, born in 1898, was a teacher, political activist, and trade unionist. Miller grew up in Adams County, Washington, attended Washington State College, and started teaching high school history in Pasco, Washington in 1926. He taught at Queen Anne High School in Seattle from 1930 until his retirement in 1963. He was active in local politics and in teachers' organizations. Miller was active in affiliates of the American Federation of Teachers, including the Washington State Federation of Teachers (WSFT), the Seattle Federation of Teachers (Local 200 of the AFT), and related organizations. He served as President of the WSFT in 1947-1948 and of the Seattle Federation of Teachers, 1952-1957. Miller died in 1978 in Seattle.
Correspondence, subject files, press clippings, reports and ephemera related to Miller's activities in politics and teachers organizations. Included are records created in the course of his work in organizations affiliated with the American Federation of Teachers. A major subgroup of records reflects Miller's work in various roles in the Seattle Federation of Teachers, Local 200 of the AFT, including correspondence (1935-1966) and newsletters. A second major subgroup derives from Miller's activism in the Washington State Federation of Teachers and its short-lived predecessor, the Washington Joint Council of Teachers. This includes correspondence, Executive Board minutes, and convention records (1937-1966). Major subject areas represented in the Elmer Miller papers are Seattle School Board election campaigns, school district finances, teacher salaries, Washington State law concerning funding of education, collective bargaining in the schools, and the competition between the National Education Association and American Federation of Teachers affiliates to represent teachers in Washington State. The papers include cassette tape recordings, with accompanying transcript, of a 1967 interview by Richard C. Berner and Steven Uthoff of Miller, describing Miller's early years in politics and the teaching profession in Seattle. There are also 6 sound cassettes of recorded interviews.
Elmer Miller, September 01, 1967, November 19, 1967, and February 10, 1969; Roger Miller, August 13, 1981
Records stored offsite; advance notice required for use.
No restrictions on access.
The visual materials that form part of this collection are described and indexed in
A Guide to the
.
Citizens' Legislative League; Washington State Council of Public Employees; Miller, Elmer,$d1898-1978$vArchives.; Miller, Elmer,$d1898-1978$vInterviews.; American Federation of Teachers.$bLocal 200 (Seattle, Wash.); Washington State Federation of Teachers.; Seattle Public Schools.; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Teachers$zWashington (State)$zSeattle.; Teachers' unions$zWashington (State)$zSeattle.; Education$zWashington (State)$zSeattle.; Collective bargaining$zWashington (State)$zSeattle.; Labor unions$zWashington (State)$zSeattle.; Labor$zWashington (State)$zSeattle.; Labor movement$zWashington (State)$zSeattle.; Personal correspondence.; Sound recordings.; Interviews.; Ephemera.; Newsletters.; Photographs.
Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor Unions; Labor History; Washington (State); Elementary and Secondary Education; Colleges and Universities; Seattle
- ELMER MILLER PERSONAL PAPERS, 1922-1972; RECORD GROUP 1 (Box-folder 1/1-11/10, 23/1-10)
  - INTERVIEWS, 1967; SERIES I (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Tape recorded interview conducted by Frank Morris, 1967. (Box-folder Tapes 36-41)
    - Transcript of interview with Elmer Miller by Richard Berner with Steven Uthoff, 1967 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - CORRESPONDENCE, 1931-1965; SERIES II (Box-folder 1/2-4/10, 23/1-2)
    - Outgoing correspondence, Undated (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1931-1947 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1951-1956 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1957-1965 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - A.F.L.-C.I.O. Committee on Political Education. King County, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Seattle Central Labor Council, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - A, 1946-1963 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - American Federation of Teachers, 1947, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 23/1-2)
    - Frank Behm, 1947 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Arnie Bergh, 1964 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Better Schools Council, 1943-1950 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Homer T. Bone, 1939 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Genette Brockhausen, 1947 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - B, 1938-1958 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - John A. Cherberg, 1959-1963 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - C, 1938-1961 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Zetta Dalton, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - May Darling, 1947-1954 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Victor F. DeGarmo, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 2/14)
    - D-E, 1937-1963 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Clayton Farrington, 1949-1956 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - F, 1959-1963 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - G, 1932-1965 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Andrew Hess, 1948-1963 (Box-folder 2/19)
    - H, 1937-1962 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - I, c. 1940 (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Henry M. Jackson, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Joint Labor Lobby, 1945-1964 (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Homer R. Jones, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 2/24)
    - J, 1943-1960 (Box-folder 2/25)
    - K, 1932-1957 (Box-folder 2/26)
    - L, 1943-1956 (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Hugh B. Mitchell, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 2/28)
    - M, 1932-1958 (Box-folder 2/29)
    - N, 1931-1964 (Box-folder 2/30)
    - John J. O'Connell, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 2/31)
    - W. J. O'Connell, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 2/32)
    - O, 1937-1963 (Box-folder 2/33)
    - P, 1937-1965 (Box-folder 2/34)
    - Q, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 2/35)
    - Albert D. Rosellini, 1952 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - R, 1942-1964 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Seattle Association of Classroom Teachers, 1937-1958 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Seattle Teacher's Association, 1958-1964 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Seattle Public Schools, 1926-1949 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Seattle Public Schools, 1950-1959 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Seattle Public Schools, 1960-1965 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - S, 1927-1960 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - T, 1939-1964 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Mon C. Wallgren, 1945-1948 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Governor's Advisory Committee on Teachers Retirement, Undated (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Washington State Superintindent of Public Instruction, 1945-1966 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Washington Education Association, 1939-1962 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Washington State Federation of Labor, 1935-1956 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Washington State Labor Council, 1958-1967 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Washington State Federation of Labor, Labor's Educational, Political League, 1947-1953 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Noel Hugh Wynne, 1945-1949 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - W, 1937-1961 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - XYZ, 1965 (Box-folder 4/10)
  - SUBJECT FILES, 1922-1972; SERIES III (Box-folder 5/1-8/1, 23/3-8)
    - Education: merit pay for teachers, 1942-1965 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Education: Seattle Queen Anne Junior-Senior High controversy, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Education: Teacher Retirement Act of 1947, 1945-1951 (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Education: teacher retirement, 1951-1963 (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Seattle High School Teachers' League, 1922-1936 (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Seattle Public Schools: Junior Achievement, 1958-1963 (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Seattle Public Schools labor management relations, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Seattle Public Schools newsletter, 1929-1958 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Seattle Public Schools newsletter, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Seattle Public Schools Professional Growth Advisory Committee (part 1 of 2), 1961-1963 (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Seattle Public Schools Professional Growth Advisory Committee (part 2 of 2), 1961-1963 (Box-folder 5/11)
    - Seattle Public Schools: minutes, 1934-1957 (Box-folder 5/12)
    - Seattle Public Schools: educators' opinion inventory, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 5/13)
    - Initiative 130 Campaign, 1938 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Interviews conducted by Political Direction Committee, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Labor - church and community relations, 1951-1960 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Labor education, 1941-1961 (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Labor-education Day, 1954 (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Labor: legislative session, 1945 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Labor / Right-to-work campaign initiative 198, 1956 (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Labor / Right-to-work campaign initiative 202, 1958 (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Labor scholarship contest, 1952-1962 (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Washington State Federation Labor, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Politics: Washington State election, 1950 (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Politics: Washington State election, 1962 (Box-folder 6/12)
    - Politics: Seattle School Board, 1932-1958 (Box-folder 6/13)
    - Politics: State Socialist Party convention, 1936 (Box-folder 6/14)
    - Politics: State and local government, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 6/15)
    - Bremerton Federation of Teachers: collective bargaining, 1960-1965 (Box-folder 6/16)
    - Resolution on the no-strike policy: draft, undated (Box-folder 23/3)
    - Seattle Federation of Teachers, 1951-1966 (Box-folder 23/4)
    - Seattle Federation of Teachers chronological highlights, circa 1965 (Box-folder 23/5)
    - Seattle School District No. 1 budget, 1949-1954 (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Seattle School District No. 1 budget, 1954-1959 (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Seattle School District No. 1 budget, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Seattle School District No. 1 budget, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 7/4)
    - Seattle School District No. 1 budget, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 7/5)
    - Seattle School District No. 1 budget, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Facts and figures about your Seattle Public Schools, 1951-1960 (Box-folder 7/7)
    - Seattle Public Schools: financing and operation, 1944-1960 (Box-folder 7/8)
    - Seattle Public Schools: Booz, Allen Hamilton report, Undated (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Seattle Public Schools: reports, 1935-1962 (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Washington State Council of Public Employees financial records, 1951 (Box-folder 23/4)
    - Washington State property tax, 1930-1934 (Box-folder 23/5)
    - Washington State property tax, 1962-1972 (Box-folder 23/6)
  - PRESS CLIPPING FILES, 1927-1972; SERIES IV (Box-folder 8/2-10/10, 23/9-10)
    - New York City teachers, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 8/2)
    - John Birch Society, 1961 (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Labor, 1943-1947 (Box-folder 8/4)
    - New Order of Cincinnatus, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 8/5)
    - University of Washington Metropolitan Tract, 1945-1952 (Box-folder 8/6)
    - School levies, 1944-1963 (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Politics - 1952 election (Box-folder 8/8)
    - Pearl Wanamaker, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 8/9)
    - Seattle School Board election, 1945 (Box-folder 8/10)
    - Seattle School Board, 1932-1950 (Box-folder 8/11)
    - State legislative session, 1965 (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Seattle High School Teachers Union, Local 200 A.F.T., 1927-1928 (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Seattle Federation of Teachers, Local 200 A.F.T., 1945-1962 (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Washington State Federation of Teachers, 1946-1960 (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Washington State Federation of Teachers, 1946-1965 (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Washington State Federation of Teachers, salary schedules, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 9/6)
    - Washington Education Association, 1952-1965 (Box-folder 9/7)
    - Natonal Education Association, 1947-1964 (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Unclassified clippings, 1932-1945 (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Washington State property tax, 1933-1972 (Box-folder 23/9)
    - Unclassified clippings, 1932-1947 (Box-folder 9/10)
    - Unclassified clippings, 1932-1954 (Box-folder 9/11)
    - Unclassified clippings, 1934-1965 (Box-folder 9/12)
    - Unclassified clippings, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 10/1)
    - Unclassified clippings, 1947 (Box-folder 23/10)
    - Unclassified clippings, 1947-1955 (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Unclassified clippings, 1948 (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Unclassified clippings, 1950-1956 (Box-folder 10/4)
    - Unclassified clippings, 1953-1959 (Box-folder 10/5)
    - Unclassified clippings, 1956 (Box-folder 10/6)
    - Unclassified clippings, 1958 (Box-folder 10/7)
    - Unclassified clippings, 1959 (Box-folder 10/8)
    - Unclassified clippings, 1960 (Box-folder 10/9)
    - Unclassified clippings, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 10/10)
  - PUBLICATIONS AND EPHEMERA, 1930-1967; SERIES V (Box-folder 10/11-11/10)
    - Politics - 1952 election (Box-folder 10/11)
    - Politics, 1938-1967 (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Education, 1944-1967 (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Labor, 1933-1965 (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Labor, 1951-1965 (Box-folder 11/4)
    - National Education Association, 1930-1964 (Box-folder 11/5)
    - Washington State Federation of Teachers, 1945-1965 (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Washington State Federation of Teachers, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 11/7)
    - Washington State Federation of Teachers - retirement, 1936-1947 (Box-folder 11/8)
    - Unclassified, 1940-1962 (Box-folder 11/9)
    - Unclassified, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 11/10)
- AMERICAN FEDERATION OF TEACHERS, LOCAL 200, 1922-1966; RECORD GROUP 2 (Box-folder 12/1-15/15)
  - CORRESPONDENCE, 1933-1966; SERIES I (Box-folder 12/1-13/14)
    - General correspondence, Undated (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1935-1942 (Box-folder 12/2)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1944-1949 (Box-folder 12/3)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1950-1952 (Box-folder 12/4)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1953 (Box-folder 12/5)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 12/6)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 12/7)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1960-1964 (Box-folder 12/8)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1933-1939 (Box-folder 12/9)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1940-1944 (Box-folder 12/10)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 12/11)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 (Box-folder 12/12)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1948 (Box-folder 12/13-14)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1949 (Box-folder 12/15)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 13/1)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1952 (Box-folder 13/2)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1953 (Box-folder 13/3-4)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 13/5)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1956 (Box-folder 13/6)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1957 (Box-folder 13/7)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1958 (Box-folder 13/8)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1959 (Box-folder 13/9)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1960 (Box-folder 13/10)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 13/11)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 13/12)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 13/13)
    - American Federation of Teachers news releases, 1935-1945 (Box-folder 13/14)
  - SUBJECT FILES, 1940-1965; SERIES II (Box-folder 14/1-15/5)
    - Salaries, 1959-1965 (Box-folder 14/1)
    - Salaries, 1953-1964 (Box-folder 14/2)
    - Salaries, 1941-1965 (Box-folder 14/3)
    - Social Security, 1942-1956 (Box-folder 14/4)
    - Teacher tenure, 1940-1956 (Box-folder 14/5)
    - Discipline, 1954-1960 (Box-folder 14/6)
    - Collective bargaining, 1957-1965 (Box-folder 14/7-8)
    - Health and welfare, 1954-1962 (Box-folder 15/1)
    - Teacher rating - Seeschaaf case, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 15/2)
    - Sachs case, 1952 (Box-folder 15/3)
    - Drafts and speaking notes, c. 1940-c. 1960 (Box-folder 15/4)
    - Financial records, 1949-1953 (Box-folder 15/5)
  - ORGANIZATIONAL RECORDS, 1928-1965; SERIES III (Box-folder 15/6-15/15)
    - Membership lists, 1943-1958 (Box-folder 15/6)
    - Local 200 News Bulletin, 1941-1960 (Box-folder 15/7)
    - Minutes of Executive Board and general membership meetings, 1943-1964 (Box-folder 15/8)
    - Meeting notices for general membership meetings, 1952-1962 (Box-folder 15/9)
    - Minutes of SFT meetings with Seattle School District representatives, 1960-1965 (Box-folder 15/10)
    - Report of committee on City Employees' Trades Council, 1945 (Box-folder 15/11)
    - Seattle Federation of Teachers chronological highlights, c. 1965 (Box-folder 15/12)
    - Local 200 constitution, Undated (Box-folder 15/13)
    - Ephemera, 1928-1963 (Box-folder 15/14)
    - Photographs, 1948, Undated (Box-folder 15/15)
- AMERICAN FEDERATION OF TEACHERS, 1936-1964; RECORD GROUP 3 (Box-folder 15/16-18/4, 23/11)
  - ORGANIZATIONAL RECORDS, 1936-1960; SERIES I (Box-folder 15/16-15/17)
    - American Federation of Teachers constitution, 1936-1960 (Box-folder 15/16)
    - American Federation of Teachers Executive Council records, 1947 (Box-folder 15/17)
  - CONVENTION RECORDS, 1940-1964; SERIES II (Box-folder 15/18-16/4, 23/11)
    - Roll call of delegates, 1958-1964 (Box-folder 15/18)
    - Convention call, 1940-1953 (Box-folder 16/1)
    - Convention documents, 1947 (Box-folder 23/11)
    - Reports to convention, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 16/2)
    - Reports to convention, 1958-1964 (Box-folder 16/3)
    - Reports of Vice-Presidents, 1948-1964 (Box-folder 16/4)
  - REPORTS AND PUBLICATIONS, 1942-1964; SERIES III (Box-folder 16/5-17/5)
    - Reports, 1942-1958 (Box-folder 16/5)
    - Manual for locals, 1959 (Box-folder 16/6)
    - Publications, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 17/1)
    - Publications, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 17/2)
    - Publications, 1959-1963 (Box-folder 17/3)
    - Brochures and leaflets (part 1 of 2), 1930s-1964 (Box-folder 17/4)
    - Brochures and leaflets (part 2 of 2), 1930s-1964 (Box-folder 17/5)
  - AFT AND AFFILIATES' CIRCULARS, NEWSLETTERS AND EPHEMERA, 1938-1966; SERIES IV (Box-folder 17/6-18/4)
    - Circulars (part 1 of 4), 1938-1966 (Box-folder 17/6)
    - Circulars (part 2 of 4), 1938-1966 (Box-folder 18/1)
    - Circulars (part 3 of 4), 1938-1966 (Box-folder 18/2)
    - Circulars (part 4 of 4), 1938-1966 (Box-folder 18/3)
    - Ephemera, 1952-1965 (Box-folder 18/4)
- WASHINGTON CLASS ROOM TEACHERS' LEAGUE, 1931-1932; RECORD GROUP 4 (Box-folder 18/5)
  - Correspondence, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 18/5)
- WASHINGTON STATE FEDERATION OF TEACHERS, 1935-1966; RECORD GROUP 5 (Box-folder 18/6-22/10)
  - CORRESPONDENCE, 1937-1966; SERIES I (Box-folder 18/6-19/5)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 18/6)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 18/7)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1945-1948 (Box-folder 18/8)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1952-1966 (Box-folder 18/9)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 18/10)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1940-1944 (Box-folder 19/1)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 19/2)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1951-1966 (Box-folder 19/3)
    - Outgoing correspondence, Undated (Box-folder 19/4)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1939-1947 (Box-folder 19/5)
  - SUBJECT FILES, 1937-1966; SERIES II (Box-folder 19/6-21/2)
    - Salary survey, 1957-1962 (Box-folder 19/6)
    - Salary schedules (part 1 of 3), 1944-1965 (Box-folder 19/7)
    - Salary schedules (part 2 of 3), 1944-1965 (Box-folder 19/8)
    - Salary schedules (part 3 of 3), 1944-1965 (Box-folder 19/9)
    - Teachers' retirement, 1937-1959 (Box-folder 19/10)
    - Tenure bill, 1942, Undated (Box-folder 19/11)
    - Salary schedules: legislation, 1947-1960 (Box-folder 19/12)
    - Legislative sessions, 1937-1948 (Box-folder 19/13)
    - Legislative sessions, 1942-1945 (Box-folder 19/14)
    - Legislative sessions, 1947-1951 (Box-folder 19/15)
    - Legislative sessions, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 19/16)
    - Legislative session, 1961 (Box-folder 20/1)
    - Legislative session (part 1 of 2), 1963 (Box-folder 20/2)
    - Legislative session (part 2 of 2), 1963 (Box-folder 20/3)
    - Legislative session (part 1 of 2), 1965 (Box-folder 20/4)
    - Legislative session (part 2 of 2), 1965 (Box-folder 20/5)
    - Legislation, Undated (Box-folder 20/6)
    - Building representative speech kit, Undated (Box-folder 20/7)
    - Proposed 1964 platform of Washington State Democratic Party (Box-folder 20/8)
    - Congressional newsletter, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 20/9)
    - Amicus petition in Spokane censorship case, Undated (Box-folder 20/10)
    - Power of public employees to strike, Undated (Box-folder 20/11)
    - Questionnaires, Undated (Box-folder 20/12)
    - School funding: news clippings, 1961 (Box-folder 20/13)
    - Notes (part 1 of 2), 1930s-1950s (Box-folder 20/14)
    - Notes (part 2 of 2), 1930s-1950s (Box-folder 20/15)
    - Reports, 1944-1962 (Box-folder 21/1)
    - Retirements: reports, 1943-1963 (Box-folder 21/2)
  - ORGANIZATIONAL RECORDS, 1935-1966; SERIES III (Box-folder 21/3-21/15)
    - WSFT Constitution, 1935-1954 (Box-folder 21/3)
    - Financial records, 1938-1965 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Bulletins, 1959-1965 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - Newsletters, 1945-1961 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - News releases, 1945-1965 (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Directory, 1949-1952 (Box-folder 21/8)
    - Executive Board Minutes, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 21/9)
    - Executive Board Minutes, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 21/10)
    - Executive Board Minutes, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 21/11)
    - Executive Board Minutes, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 21/12)
    - Executive Board Minutes, 1950-1958 (Box-folder 21/13)
    - Executive Board Minutes, 1959-1963 (Box-folder 21/14)
    - Executive Board Minutes, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 21/15)
  - CONVENTION RECORDS, 1937-1966; SERIES IV (Box-folder 22/1-22/10)
    - Proceedings and resolutions, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 22/1)
    - Proceedings and resolutions, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 22/2)
    - Proceedings and resolutions, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 22/3)
    - Proceedings and resolutions, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 22/4)
    - Proceedings and resolutions, 1947 (Box-folder 22/5)
    - Proceedings and resolutions, 1948-1953 (Box-folder 22/6)
    - Proceedings and resolutions, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 22/7)
    - Proceedings and resolutions, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 22/8)
    - Proceedings and resolutions, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 22/9)
    - Resolutions, Undated (Box-folder 22/10)